[
    {
        "front": "のぼります ❘\n「やまに～」",
        "back": "climb [a mountain]",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "とまります ❘\n「ホテルに～」",
        "back": "stay [at a hotel]",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "そうじします ❘❘❘",
        "back": "clean (a room)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "せんたくします❘❘❘",
        "back": "wash (clothes)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "れんしゅうします ❘❘❘",
        "back": "practice",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "なります ❘",
        "back": "to become",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ねむい",
        "back": "sleepy",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "つよい",
        "back": "strong",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "よわい",
        "back": "weak",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょうしが いい",
        "back": "be in good condition",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょうしが わるい",
        "back": "be in bad condition",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ちょうし",
        "back": "condition",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ゴルフ",
        "back": "golf (～を します: play golf)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "すもう",
        "back": "sumo wrestling",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "パチンコ",
        "back": "pinball game (～を します: play pachinko)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "おちゃ",
        "back": "tea ceremony",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ひ",
        "back": "day, date",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "いちど",
        "back": "once",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "いちども",
        "back": "not once, never (used with negative)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "だんだん",
        "back": "gradually",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "もうすぐ",
        "back": "soon",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "おかげさまで",
        "back": "thank you (Expressing gratitude for help received)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "かんぱい",
        "back": "Cheers! / bottoms up",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "じつは",
        "back": "actually, the truth is",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ダイエット",
        "back": "diet (～を します: go on a diet)",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "なんかいも",
        "back": "many times",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "しかし",
        "back": "but, however",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "むり[な]",
        "back": "impossible, excessive, difficult",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "からだに いい",
        "back": "good for one’s health",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    },
    {
        "front": "ケーキ",
        "back": "cake",
        "chapter": "N5 C19"
    }
]